Miss Tang, don't waste your energy.
His Highness won't open the door.
What exactly happened?
His Majesty has issued a decree
for the officials to discuss the crown prince nomination.
Although I don't understand politics,
having lived in the manor for a while
and learned a few things,
this should be a good thing for His Highness.
It is a good thing.
Jingxuan has been in politics for less than two years.
He is praised by the officials
and has gained a great reputation.
Then why?
The tallest tree in the forest
is the first to be blown down.
A few days ago, a rumor suddenly spread
that Jingxuan caused his biological mother's death
and is abandoned by heaven.
If he is made the crown prince,
it will bring disaster to the country.
The late Empress indeed died in childbirth.
His Highness never celebrates his birthday.
It's to mourn Her Majesty.
I wonder who would
poke His Highness's sore spot like this.
It's truly insane.
There are many causes for difficult labor,
especially for a firstborn.
How can the baby be entirely to blame?
That may be so,
but Jingxuan's inner demons are hard to dispel.
Mr. Su, could you do me a favor?
What do you mean, Miss Tang?
As a son,
he deserves to know the truth.
You're right.
Perhaps only the truth can give him peace.
That's how it happened.
Here are the medical records and prescriptions from back then.
I've circled the questionable parts.
The testimonies of the royal physicians, maids, and midwives from back then
who are still alive are all here.
Are you saying
someone replaced my mother's postpartum hemostatic medicine
with blood-activating medicine,
which killed her?
And the method was clever
and extremely covert.
Unless you are an experienced healer,
it's hard to detect.
If I don't avenge this,
I am not fit to be her son.
Jingxuan.
We have plenty of time.
You must not be hasty now.
I heard from Young Master Su
that His Majesty has dealt with
all those who spread the rumors.
What else is on Your Highness's mind?
Why didn't you dodge?
Your Highness wouldn't hurt me.
Your Highness's condition has improved.
Allow me to think for a few days
before prescribing the right medicine.
This is my specially made ointment.
It works wonders for relieving headaches.
I added osmanthus to it,
so it doesn't smell bad.
Is there any story behind your birthmark?
It's just a birthmark.
What story could there be?
Besides, since I fell off the cliff,
I've lost my memory.
Even if there is a story,
I wouldn't remember it.
Why are you so curious about my birthmark, Your Highness?
I once heard
that a person's birthmark
is a trace left from a past life.
It's a tear shed by a lover in a past life,
so they can find each other
and rekindle their romance.
You look so aloof, Your Highness.
How can you believe a storyteller's tale?
Don't you believe it, Miss Tang?
Confucius never talked about the supernatural.
Tang Zhiluo,
can I trust you?
Whether you trust me or not
is entirely up to you, Your Highness.
I don't need to say more.
What is this?
It's called Soul Jade.
I don't know where it came from either.
I only know
that keeping it with me
prevents my headaches.
It seems to be a pair with your birthmark.
How can there be such a coincidence in this world?
Your Highness, may I borrow this jade pendant?
I don't mean anything else.
I just think this Soul Jade
might be able to cure your headaches.
Take it.
Thank you, Your Highness.
I will return it as soon as possible.
The shapes are so similar.
Pinellia, Gastrodia,
and...
I haven't seen you in such high spirits for a long time.
I came to tell you
that Miss Tang has met with Yuwen Jia.
Don't worry.
There seems to be a misunderstanding.
Miss Tang specifically asked to meet me
just to tell me about
my sixth brother's soul jade?
Exactly.
That piece of jade
indeed has a trick to it.
It can determine Lord Shuo's life and death.
I found out
that piece of jade
was soaked in Shanyue Lingzhi water,
which is why it has such a miraculous effect.
I remember
that Your Highness
happens to have one.
You want to ask for my Lingzhi, don't you?
It's not difficult to get this Lingzhi.
But miss,
you need to pay a corresponding price.
Your Highness, I have already...
Zhiluo,
why were you behind me?
That jade can cure Your Highness's headache.
I also got Lingzhi from Prince Yu.
Stop talking.
I'll go get the imperial physician.
It's okay. You'll be fine.
Imperial physician! Imperial physician!
It's too late.
It's too late, Your Highness.
I am a doctor myself.
It's a pity...
It's a pity that in the end, I still couldn't...
couldn't repay you.
Tang Zhiluo!
This is what I told you.
Dying for him in every life,
living for him in every life.
This is the price you pay as a goddess.